This video includes a discussion of serious crimes, which may be disturbing for some viewers,
so I wanted to let you know that up front.
But I think it's necessary to talk about these crimes in some detail for reasons that
will become apparent.
In the small town of Visalia, California, in the mid-1970s, one of the state's most prolific
criminals got his start.
He repeatedly broke into houses and stole small items, like cash, coins, and jewelry.
He was dubbed the Visalia Ransacker, but soon his crimes escalated.
Six months later, 1976, he moves up to to Sacramento and over the course of the next three years
is moving all across northern California committing numerous sexual assaults over 50 sexual assaults.
Here he was called the East Area rapist. The police are saying lock up tight.
Sacramento's infamous East Area rapists may still be in town.
And then in 1979, he moves down to Southern California starting in Santa Barbara and starts
killing.
And he was known as the original night stalker in Southern California.
Variously known as the East Area rapist and the original night stalker, these were brutal,
meticulously planned crimes that spanned numerous California counties
between 1976 and 1986.
Police believed that all of these crimes were committed
by the same person, now known as the Golden State Killer.
How was it known that these were committed by the same person?
Investigators were relying on MMO.
MMO, MODIS operandi, is basically how a criminal will commit a crime.
I was wearing some type of...
I'm a master who had wearing shorts in a t-shirt. The Golden Snake Killer had very distinct
of them up. What he would do is he would wake into a house with a gun, a house with a man and
a woman, he would tie them up, tell the man I'm going to put plates on your back.
If I hear those plates move, I'm going to kill your wife and then kill you, take the
life into another room and sexually assault her.
Then he would go through the house for, however much time eating, stealing stuff, stealing
little things or whatever, and then he would leave.
How is he not caught based on fingerprint evidence?
Well, he deleted fingerprints.
He always wore masks.
He always had gloves off.